in solidity when you want to store a
当您要存储数据集合时，可以使用数组
collection of data you either use array
or mapping in this video we'll go over
或本视频中的映射，我们将介绍如何创建映射以及如何获取
how to create a mapping and how to get
set and delete a value from a mapping
首先设置和删除映射中的值什么是映射映射
first what is a mapping mapping in
solidity is like a dictionary in Python
坚固性就像Python中的字典或JavaScript映射中的映射
or a map in JavaScript mapping allows
you to disable data add a key that you
要禁用数据，请添加您指定的键，然后在以下位置获取该值
specify and then later get that value at
the key now Python allows you to iterate
现在的关键是Python使您可以遍历字典和JavaScript
through a dictionary and JavaScript
allows you to iterate through the map so
允许您遍历地图，以便提供字典或地图
giving a dictionary or a map you can get
all of the keys or all of the values
所有键或其中的所有值，但是牢固性不能
from it however in solidity you cannot
iterate through the mapping and in order
遍历映射，然后创建可以迭代的映射
to create a map that you can iterate
you'll have to use a combination of
您将不得不使用映射帮派数组的组合并存储密钥
mapping gang arrays and store the keys
in an array the other downside of using
在数组中，使用映射和坚固性的另一个缺点是您可以
a mapping and solidity is that you can
get the size of a mapping so in summary
获取映射的大小，因此总而言之，映射对于快速查找和
a mapping is good for fast look ups and
if you want to iterate through a mapping
如果要遍历映射，则必须做一些额外的工作
then you'll have to do some extra work
and write extra code now to create your
并立即编写额外的代码来创建您的映射，您可以从关键字开始
mapping you start with the keyword
mapping followed by the key type and the
紧随其后的键类型和值类型的映射将其声明为public和
value type will declare it as public and
call this mapping my map
将此映射称为我的地图，所以这里我的地图是来自地址的映射
so here my map is a mapping from address
to you and the key type for a mapping
给您，并且映射的键类型必须是内置值，请输入字符串
has to be a built-in value type a string
or bytes so for example you end boolean
或字节，例如，您结束布尔值和地址都是有效的键类型，
and address are all valid key types the
value type of a mapping can be any type
映射的值类型可以是任何类型，例如，它可以是难得的buin旅游
for example it can be a rare buin tour
another mapping the syntax for reading
另一个映射从映射中读取值的语法类似于
of value from a map is similar to how
you would access an array we'll create a
您将访问一个数组，我们将创建一个返回值的公共函数
public function that returns the value
given a key since the key type of my map
给定一个键，因为我的地图的键类型是一个地址，但函数会接受
is an address yet function will take in
an address as input the value type of my
输入的地址是我地图的值类型，是一个新的整数，因此我们
map is a new int so our
Shango return on you and inside the
Shango返回您，并且在函数内部，我们返回的UM值是
function we return the UM value that is
stored inside my map at the address
存储在我的地图中的地址处，请注意，我们访问地图的方式
notice that the way we access a mapping
is similar to how we access an array now
类似于我们现在访问数组的方式，不像数组，您将永远不会获得
unlike an array you would never get an
error from accessing the mapping at a
即使访问键处的映射是错误的，也无法访问键处的映射
key even if the mapping at the key was
never set if the belly was never set
如果从未设置腹部，则从不设置，那么坚固性将返回默认值
then solidity will return the default
value in this case it will be zero
在这种情况下，它的值将为零，这是您为映射设置值的方式是
the way you set a value for a mapping is
also similar to how you will update an
也类似于您将在此处创建一个函数的情况下更新数组元素的方式
array element here I created a function
that takes in an address and the value
它需要一个地址和要在该地址设置的值，在这里我们
to be set at that address and here we
update the value of my map at the
通过分配新值并在地址处更新我的地图的值，并
address by assigning the new value and
the way you would delete a element from
您从映射中删除元素的方式也类似于您
a mapping is also similar to how you
would do the element from an array you
会从您以关键字delete开头的数组中执行元素
start with the keyword delete followed
by the location inside the mapping to
根据要删除的映射内的位置，我们要删除的值
delete here we're deleting the value
that is stored inside my map at this
存储在我的地图中此地址的位置，就像删除数组一样
address just like an array the delete
keyword actually doesn't remove the
关键字实际上不会从映射中删除元素，因此在此之后
element from a mapping so after this
operation my map at this address will be
操作我在此地址的地图的值为0现在让我们尝试调用这些
the value 0 now let's try calling these
functions in remix so go ahead and
可以进行混音，所以现在就可以编译和部署合同
compile and deploy the contract now
we're gonna need an address to call
我们需要一个地址来调用这些函数，所以我只想复制
these functions so I'm just gonna copy
the address from the contract that was
现在正在部署的合同中的地址称为cat，您将
deploying now called cat and you'll
notice that the function did not fail
请注意，该函数没有失败，而是返回了值0甚至
and instead it returned the value 0 even
though we haven't set any value at this
尽管我们没有在该地址设置任何值，所以这表明我们的映射
address so this shows that our mapping
always returns a value even if it was
即使从未设置过，也总是返回一个值，在这种情况下，它将
never set and in that case it will
return a default value and this is why
返回默认值，这就是为什么我们在这里调用下一个set函数时得到0的原因
we got a 0 here next call a set function
and you can verify that the value was
您可以通过调用get函数来验证该值是否已设置
set by calling the get function
afterwards finally call the remove
之后，最后调用remove函数，您可以验证
function and you can verify that the
value was deleted by calling the get 4
再次调用get 4下巴删除了值，从而涵盖了如何创建
chin again so that covers how to create
your mapping get set and delete your
在此视频中，您的映射已设置并从映射中删除了您的值，我们
value from a mapping in this video we
went over how to create your mapping and
讨论了如何创建映射以及如何执行基本操作（如读取）
how to do basic operations like read
write and delete value for my mapping
为我的映射编写和删除值，例如Python中的字典或Windows中的映射
like a dictionary in Python or a map in
JavaScript mapping and solidity is good
JavaScript映射和坚固性有助于快速查找，这是您需要做的一件事
for fast look ups one thing you need to
keep in mind about mapping is that you
请记住，映射是您无法迭代它们，也无法获取
cannot iterate them and you cannot get
the size of a mapping so if you need to
映射的大小，因此如果您需要遍历地图或知道有多少
iterate through a map or know how many
elements are inside a mapping then
元素在映射内，那么您将不得不编写一些额外的代码来
you'll have to write some extra code to
make it work well that's all I got for
使其运作良好，这就是我获得的这段视频的全部内容，感谢您收看一个
this video thanks for watching have a
nice week and I'll see you in the next
美好的一周，我会在下一个视频中再见
video